[♪ opening music begins]
[♪ opening music ends]
[♪ cheerful music]
[soft breathing]
[EMA] Honestly, Lara,
Mari's been at school
all day and you haven't
done a single thing.
Huh?
The window you broke
cost Y¥100,000.
-Right.
-But you...
STRAWBERRY DAIFUKU
See, I told you they were good.
OCEAN CREATURES
OCEAN ENCYCLOPEDIA
We work hard here.
That's our rule.
Rule? I didn't know
there were rules.
[EMA] There are now.
Mari, that includes you too.
You said you wanted
money for some Airheads?
-[MARI] AirPods Pro.
-Isn't that what you have?
They're old.
I need a new pair.
I can't keep up.
If you want them,
get a job and earn the money.
But I don't even know if getting
a job is something I can do.
It's not all bad, you know.
I actually met my wife while
I was working at a job.
Really?
So then I might meet
my prince at a job?
Hmm... maybe?
[gasps] I'll do it!
I'm going to go to work!
You wrote until
pretty late, huh?
[MARI] It was her first
time writing by hand,
so I stayed up all night
to make it look good.
Well, it's good to prepare
yourself for the day.
Although, the real
work starts now.
I'm Mari Otsu.
I'm a high school student.
My name is Lara. I'm a princess
of the royal family.
I can only work once a week
'cause I prioritize boxing.
Have I ever worked before?
No, not at all!
The higher hourly wage can be,
the better it is for me.
What am I good at?
Well, I'm great at
telling starfish apart.
[both sigh]
I wonder if everyone just does
not want me to work for them.
I was sure I was
going to get the job.
[both sigh]
Don't worry, girls.
You should just keep applying.
Plenty of jobs out there.
There's sure to be something
perfect for both.
Just you wait.
Oh, by the way, Mr. Makoto,
what do you do for work?
Mari, show her my camera.
That is my work gear.
This is your job?
It's a job where I
press that button.
Huh?! No way!
Is there really a job that easy?
Lara, why not give it a go?
-This one's a little bit easier.
-Huh?
[Lara sighs]
You won't make any money
seeing as you're not a pro.
But press the shutter
and you can capture
any scene right in front of you.
Mess up, and
you can't delete it
like on a smartphone.
-See what you can capture.
-Wow.
[sighs]
Ah! A castle?
I'm pretty sure that's
a cake shop.
Cake?
I'd love to make
a cake sometime,
especially... in
a place this lovely.
I might even meet
my prince there.
OFFICE
[MANAGER] Oh, you
applied together?
[BOTH] Yes.
You're certainly keen.
Why did you apply?
I applied because I love
sweets and cake, and I'll work
harder than anyone else!
Hmm, but there are a
lot of kids like you
who just quit as soon
as they get bored.
Any part-time experience?
Well, the thing is, I've never
passed an interview before.
Huh? How many did you apply for?
I think about 20.
20?
If you apply many times,
you usually get hired.
Especially if you say you're
the hardest-working
person in the world.
Oh, right!
Your kingdom-— um,
I mean company!
I really resonate with your
company's founding philosophy.
Either way, my strength is that
I never give up.
So my weakness is that I'm
kind of stubborn.
And if I had to describe myself,
I'm like a dried squid.
A bit rough around
the edges, but I, I...
[gasp]
I would...
absolutely die for cake!
[Lara breathing heavily]
-And you?
-I wouldn't die for cake.
Right.
Hi! Nice to meet you both.
Mari, you'll be
on the sales floor with me.
-Lara, you'll be in the kitchen.
-[BOTH] Okay.
Your lockers are over there.
LARA
Hey, Mari,
what does this say here?
-Says, I'd die for cake.
-Huh?
[background chatter]
[♪ cheerful music playing]
[LARA] Wow!
Uh...
I can't believe I actually
get to make a cake!
Hey, Mari, come
over here, new girl.
-We'll start with washing up.
-Don't I get to make any cake?
Washing up is an important
step in the cake-making process.
Right, I see.
I'll do my best!
[grunts]
[grunts intensify]
There's still more
washing up to do.
-Mr. Manager?
-Yes, what?
I'd really like to start
making cakes soon, please.
Told you that washing up is
an important job, right?
Yes, you did,
but this is exhausting.
That's right,
that's what hard work is.
Work is basically torture.
Sorry about that. Manager's
a bit strict, isn't he?
It's torture.
Looks like the washing's
piling up again.
Let's do our best.
Come on, Lara.
[wails]
[cash register rings]
[sighs]
[LARA] Just what is it
I'm trying to do exactly?
[WITCH] Indeed, you mustn't
forget the reason you're here.
But do you think you'll find
the prince there?
[ominous tone]
You know, I'm not really sure.
It could be a
customer in the shop.
Huh?
Or maybe not.
ANDEKEN
Good morning.
I was wondering-—
Shh.
[magical chime]
[gasps]
Wow, it's delicious!
You're a genius!
-Mr. Manager?
-Huh?
I would like to make a
cake soon, please.
You're the only one
having fun here.
Huh, you sure?
You said that work is
going to be torture.
Hmm. You know,
work isn't torture.
It's actually quite fun.
Today, at least.
Today?
If you want to help
out, I'll let you.
-[Lara sighs]
-Really?
You've got your work
cut out for you now.
Stick with me until the new
product is finished.
-Are you ready?
-[wails]
[♪ upbeat music]
Alright, we're making
a peach tart.
YAMANASHI PEACH
DAICHI FARMS
Yes, peel this one.
[♪ upbeat music]
[grunts]
Actually, peel this one instead.
The cream's proportions are key.
Hmm, it's not right.
Still not right.
Hey, Lara, make sure you don't
get any shells in there.
Lara, can you start preparing
the sponge cake, please?
Lara?
Lara!
ANDEKEN
[magic sound]
[workers cheer and applaud]
It's too early to celebrate.
We've gotta get
this product ready.
Hey, Lara, let's get to peeling!
Yes, right!
-Good work today.
-Yeah, we all worked hard.
See you later.
Thanks for today.
You've been a big help.
You worked hard today.
Be proud of yourself.
[♪ soft piano music]
[cat meows]
I wonder how many days
I've been working now.
I mustn't forget that I really
need to find true love soon.
[♪ soft piano music]
Big sis, I don't understand.
Why won't you come to see me?
Lady Lisa, aren't you
going to see her?
[♪ soft piano music]
Lara...
[car starts]
I promise... I'll protect you.
[magic sound]
[♪ soft piano music]
I seriously can't just
keep working like this.
It needs to end, and soon.
Mr. Manager, can you tell me
how much I'm getting
paid this month?
Well, I'm not sure.
It's probably around Y¥70,000.
70,000?
Ema told me
to earn Y¥100,000, so...
Well, first, focus on doing the
work in front of you correctly.
Once you've improved
step by step, and
when you're able to handle
bigger jobs with ease,
then I'll raise your wage.
I have to do bigger jobs?
Whoa, Lara, you're not ready
for the oven just yet.
Oh, but please, I need to
do the big jobs.
Huh?
Hey, I've seen this before.
You press this
button here, right?
Whoa, no!
If you press it at the wrong
time, it'll ruin everything.
You absolutely
must not touch it.
Hey, please, can you teach me
how to do your job?
Not right now.
Next time.
Lara, come on, you need
to peel these peaches.
[♪ lighthearted piano music]
I really can't keep
going like this.
[♪ lighthearted piano music]
But I guess...
I have no choice.
[oven timer beeps]
[sighs]
[oven timer keeps beeping]
Why did you touch the button?
I'm sorry!
I thought I had to stop it.
It was just an alarm, you know.
I'll go tell the manager.
I guess he'll be
working late tonight.
Oh wait, let me try to take
care of it first.
I can make them again,
I know I can.
Lara, wait.
I'm partly to blame for this.
Just support me like you
always do. That's all I need.
OFFICE
I don't want to add more
stress to your life...
but what's the rush?
Well?
Ema told me I had to
go out and get a job,
and this is the only place
that would hire me.
But I've lost sight of why I'm
working here in the first place.
I'm supposed to be out there.
Trying to find my prince.
It's okay if you want to quit.
There's no shame in it.
[WITCH] What exactly are you
doing day in and day out?
You haven't forgotten about
your family, have you?
You don't need to worry.
Tomorrow I'll tell
them I'm quitting.
Quitting because
you messed up?
-No, that's not it.
-[MARI] Hmm.
What about the money? You know
grandma's gonna get mad again.
Either way....
I think you tried your best.
[♪ melancholic piano music]
ANDEKEN
[LARA] Today is my last day.
[♪ piano music continues]
I'M WILLING TO DIE FOR CAKE!
[LARA] Good morning.
Lara! You're early.
Yes! Good morning.
Can't go into the kitchen
without changing first.
You'll bring in dust.
So, um, Mr. Manager?
What is it?
I- well...
Everyone!
I'm so sorry for
causing trouble!
Yesterday!
Yeah, it was really tough
after you did that.
-So tough.
-Oh.
Don't worry about it.
It happens all the time.
In fact, Ishiyama here makes
even worse mistakes.
He always burns things.
Exactly! And you never
mix the cream properly.
-Go change your clothes now.
-Yes.
I think we should have a
welcome party very soon.
[EMA] That's plenty for
the window, thanks.
And the rest is all yours.
Huh?
Well, you worked hard for it,
didn't you?
[gasps]
With this much money,
I can buy anything I want!
Mari! I'll buy you
cocoa every day!
Don't waste your money already.
[♪ soft piano music
and woman singing]
[background chatter]
[LARA] So she calls
Mr. Manager Seta?
I mean, she's a
senior after all.
How interesting.
So tell me, what's your plan,
huh? You said you were
quitting earlier.
Mm-hmm.
[LARA] But lately I've been
thinking about something.
It's just...
I've been wanting to
know more about you,
about humans,
for a long time now.
Washing dishes and
peeling fruit is hard work,
but the more I get to
know about your world,
the more I see a new
side of you all,
which makes me want to learn
even more about you.
I really like this feeling
because I believe it's going to
lead me to the true love that
I've been searching for.
I think so.
Hmm, so does that mean
you're not quitting after all?
Yes, for now...
I think I'll stay.
[♪ soft piano music
and woman singing]
-[LARA] I'll take 20.
-[WOMAN] Sure thing,
Mari...
I wonder how many you'll eat.
Lara.
[gasps]
Lisa?!
You have legs.
[LISA] I've wanted to
see you for so long.
All this time I've been waiting
for you to come back to life.
[LARA] But how?
Surely not Lady Witch's potion?
[LISA] I'm sorry, I didn't want
you to see me in
this hideous form.
My beloved Lara, you're such
a special princess.
The only one who will
save us with your light.
But why did you take
the potion again?
What on earth made
you do such a thing?
Because I...
I want to save our family
and everyone else.
But to do that...
I need to find a human
partner and fall in love.
[gasps]
-The witch told you that?
-What?
Listen, Lara...
you should have learned
this lesson 200 years ago.
A mermaid and a human,
there's absolutely no way
they can love each other.
No way at all.
[ominous tone]
[Lara sobs] But...
things might be
different tomorrow.
Sending Kota there was
the right decision.
I will not allow a mermaid
and a human to fall in love.
You don't need any of them,
not that house, nor that girl.
That girl?
[♪ tense music]
[pants]
[sighs]
Everyone!
[magic sound]
[♪ tense music continues]
Mari!
[magic sound]
[growling]
[gasps]
[gasps] It's... moving.
Kota!
[tires screeching]
[♪ tense music ends]
[♪ closing music begins]
TRANSLATION:
SACHIKO TAKAHASHI
TIMING: ANDY ELLIS
EDITING AND TYPESETTING:
ASHLEY BARBOZA
QUALITY CONTROL:
RILEY DALTON
TRANSLATION CHECK:
SRIRAM GURUNATHAN
[♪ closing music ends]
[panting]
Mari!
[voices from the TV]
-What's up?
-Hey, welcome back!
Just in time.
Again? Seriously?
Hmm?
[crying]
I'm so glad.
I'm such an idiot.
[LARA] I guess I just
jumped to conclusions.
[sirens wailing in distance]
SHIGA
TO BE CONTINUED